Huy Nguyen

⋈ huynguyenaui@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/huy-nguyen-454a6016a

github.com/HuyNguyenAu

huynguyen.space

About Me

I'm a curious individual and an avid learner with professional full stack software engineering experience. I thrive on tackling interesting and difficult challenges.

Skills

Languages:	C#	Typescript	Javascript
Libraries:	.NET 6.0	React	NextJS
Tools:	Docker	Azure	Figma
Platforms:	Windows	Linux	MacOS

Education

Computer and Network Engineering (Honours)
Mar 2016 to Mar 2020

Work Experience

Software Engineer

JET Charge | Oct 2021 - Present

- On-premise and autonomous Electric
 Vehicle (EV) charging load management
 system, developing both a user-friendly web
 interface green field project and
 implementing backend APIs.
- Cloud-based platform focused on Electric Vehicle smart-charging management and optimisation. This encompassed implementing the web interface and backend APIs.

Graduate IT Specialist

EnergyLocals | Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

- Implemented specialised programs, utilising Azure services for efficient processing and management of AEMO settlements.
- Streamlined data management processes by implementing automated backup solutions for databases and IT systems.

IT Specialist

EnergyLocals | Sep 2020 - Oct 2021

- Creation and implementation of a customized customer sign-up journey under the umbrella of white-label branding, streamlining and enhancing user onboarding.
- Managed the deployment and maintenance of Virtual Private Servers (VPS), ensuring seamless functionality and system reliability.
- Government and business reporting tasks utilizing SQL, demonstrating a keen understanding of data management and reporting principles.
- Conducted the installation, testing, and configuration of IT equipment, contributing to a robust and well-functioning technological infrastructure.

Projects

GPT Decoder

Apr 2023 - Nov 2023

A simple GPT decoder for educational purposes following Andrej Karpathy's "Let's build GPT: from scratch, in code, spelled out" with some optimisations.

Wobbly ML

Jul 2022 - March 2023

A machine learning library using the the Neural Networks From Scratch book.

Lox Crystal Lang

Aug 2021 - Nov 2022

A Crystal programming language implementation of the Lox programming language using the Crafting Interpreters book.